Guide to the Portrait Collection, 1673-1962
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Portrait Collection
1673-1962
Vassar College. Library
4.6 cubic feet (5 oversize boxes, 8 mapcase folders)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Artificial collection of portraits of significant figures in history, literature and the arts.
Scope and Content Note
Artificial collection of portraits of significant figures in history, literature and the arts. Created and added to over several decades for the purposes of library instruction.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Document Types:
Portraits
VCL Categories:
Art and Artists
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, February 2009.
Acquisition Information
Samuel S. Constant portrait was received in 2004 (A2004-017); other items acquired from various sources.
Container List
- Agrippa, Henricus Cornelius, undated (Folder 1.01 (Oversize))
- Ann, Queen, undated (Folder 1.01 (Oversize))
- Antino O., undated (Folder 1.01 (Oversize))
- Antonino, Marcus Aurelius, undated (Folder 1.01 (Oversize))
- Ariosto, undated (Folder 1.02 (Oversize))
- Aristotle, undated (Folder 1.02 (Oversize))
- Arnold, Matthew, undated (Folder 1.02 (Oversize))
- Audobon, John J., undated (Folder 1.02 (Oversize))
- Bartlett, Paul, undated (Folder 1.03 (Oversize))
- Beerbohm, Max, 1911 (Folder 1.03 (Oversize))
- Beerbohm, Max, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1927 (Folder 1.03 (Oversize))
- Bellingham, John, 18 May 1812 (Folder 1.03 (Oversize))
- Benet, Stephen Vincent, 1943 (Folder 1.04 (Oversize))
- Bentivoglio, Cardinal Guido, undated (Folder 1.04 (Oversize))
- Blackstone, Sir William, 1874 (Folder 1.04 (Oversize))
- Blashfield, Edwin Howland, undated (Folder 1.05 (Oversize))
- Bodley, Sir Thomas, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.05 (Oversize))
- Bojer, Johan, 1920 (Folder 1.06 (Oversize))
- Bombast, undated (Folder 1.06 (Oversize))
- Bonaparte, Napoleon, undated (Folder 1.06 (Oversize))
- Brougham, Lord, undated (Folder 1.07 (Oversize))
- Buck, Pease S., undated (Folder 1.07 (Oversize))
- Bullen, Ann, 1738 (Folder 1.07 (Oversize))
- Bullion, Cardinal de, 1673 (Folder 1.07 (Oversize))
- Burroughs, John, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.08 (Oversize))
- Camden, Charles Pratt Earl, 1794 (Folder 1.09 (Oversize))
- Carter, Elizabeth, 1788 (Folder 1.09 (Oversize))
- Cartwright, Major, 1831 (Folder 1.09 (Oversize))
- Cesare, C., undated (Folder 1.10 (Oversize))
- Chamberlain, Neville, 1938 (Folder 1.10 (Oversize))
- Charron, Pierre, undated (Folder 1.10 (Oversize))
- Chase, Salmon P., undated (Folder 1.11 (Oversize))
- Christian VII, 1768 (Folder 1.11 (Oversize))
- Cibelle, undated (Folder 1.11 (Oversize))
- Clemenceal, M. George, 1918; (2 item) (Folder 1.12 (Oversize))
- Condillac, 1780 (Folder 1.13 (Oversize))
- Constant, Samuel S., undated (Folder 1.14 (Oversize))
- Cooper, undated (Folder 1.13 (Oversize))
- Cowleius (Cowley), Abrahamus, undated (Folder 1.13 (Oversize))
- Cromwell, Oliver, undated (Folder 1.14 (Oversize))
- De La Mare, Walter, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Defoe, undated (Folder 1.15 (Oversize))
- Dickens, Charles "Boz", 1838 (Folder 1.15 (Oversize))
- Dickens, Charles, His Wife, and Sister, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.15 (Oversize))
- Diderot, undated (Folder 1.15 (Oversize))
- Dodgson, Campbell, 1934 (Folder 1.16 (Oversize))
- Drinkwater, John, 1919 (Folder 1.16 (Oversize))
- Dumas, Alexandre, 1902 (Folder 1.16 (Oversize))
- Duns, Jean, undated (Folder 1.17 (Oversize))
- Eddington, A. S., 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Edward VIII, King, 1936; (3 items) (Folder 1.17 (Oversize))
- Egan, Pierce, 1832 (Folder 1.17 (Oversize))
- Einstein, Albert, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1956 (Folder M1 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Elizabeth, Queen, undated (Folder 1.18 (Oversize))
- Elizabeth II, Queen and King George VI, 1936, 1937; (2 items) (Folder 2.04 (Oversize))
- Emerson, Ralph Waldo, undated (Folder 1.18 (Oversize))
- Evarts, William, 1884 (Folder M1 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Fabre, J. H., 1914 (Folder 1.19 (Oversize))
- Faguet, undated (Folder 1.19 (Oversize))
- Fenelon (Francois de Salignac de la Mothe), undated (Folder 1.19 (Oversize))
- Ferdinand I, 1922 (Folder 1.20 (Oversize))
- Ferrimontanus, undated (Folder 1.20 (Oversize))
- Fisher, Bishop of Rochester, undated (Folder 1.20 (Oversize))
- Foch, Marshal, undated; (3 items) (Folder 1.21 (Oversize))
- France, Anatole, 1914, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.22 (Oversize))
- Franklin, Benjamin, 1778, 1950; (2 items) (Folder 1.22 (Oversize))
- Franklin, Benjamin, 1859 (Folder M7 (Map Case - Drawer 31))
- Frederic II, 1756 (Folder 2.01 (Oversize))
- Galba, Ser., undated (Folder 2.01 (Oversize))
- Garibaldi, Giuseppe, 1919 (Folder 2.01 (Oversize))
- Gates, Horatio, undated (Folder 2.01 (Oversize))
- George I, King, 1746 (Folder 2.02 (Oversize))
- George IV, King, undated (Folder 2.02 (Oversize))
- George V, King, 1928, 1929, 1935, undated; (4 items) (Folder 2.03 (Oversize))
- George VI, King and Queen Elizabeth II, 1936, 1937; (2 items) (Folder 2.04 (Oversize))
- George, M. Lloyd, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.04 (Oversize))
- Gerard, undated (Folder 2.05 (Oversize))
- Giove, undated (Folder 2.05 (Oversize))
- Giraud, Jacob Post, Jr., undated (Folder 2.05 (Oversize))
- Gladstone, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.05 (Oversize))
- Gneifenau, undated (Folder 2.06 (Oversize))
- Goethe, undated (Folder 2.06 (Oversize))
- Green, John Richard, 1929 (Folder 2.06 (Oversize))
- Gutenberg, undated (Folder 2.07 (Oversize))
- Harrington, Lucy, undated (Folder 2.07 (Oversize))
- Hauptmann, Gerhart, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Hawker, Robert, 1820 (Folder 2.07 (Oversize))
- Hayes, President, and Cabinet, 1880 (Folder 2.08 (Oversize))
- Hill, Lord, 1819 (Folder 2.08 (Oversize))
- Hillman, Sydney, undated (Folder 2.08 (Oversize))
- Hitler, Adolph, undated (Folder 2.09 (Oversize))
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Senior, approximately 1875; (2 items) (Folder 2.09 (Oversize))
- Hoover, Herbert, 1925 (Folder 2.09 (Oversize))
- Hoover, Herbert, undated (Folder M1 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Humboldt, Alexander von, 1856 (Folder M6 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Hume, David, 1806 (Folder 2.09 (Oversize))
- James, Thomas, undated (Folder 2.09 (Oversize))
- Jefferson, Thomas, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.10 (Oversize))
- Jenkins, Henry, 1846 (Folder 2.10 (Oversize))
- Joachim, Joseph, undated (Folder 2.11 (Oversize))
- Joffre, General, 1915 (Folder M2 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- John, Augustus, undated (Folder 2.11 (Oversize))
- Johnson, Samuel, undated (Folder 2.11 (Oversize))
- Kent, Duchess Of, 1818? (Folder 2.11 (Oversize))
- Kruell, Gustov, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.12 (Oversize))
- Laud, Archbishop, undated (Folder 2.13 (Oversize))
- Lavisse, undated (Folder 2.13 (Oversize))
- Langtree, L., undated (Folder 2.13 (Oversize))
- Leapold, Prince of Saxe Cobura, 1817 (Folder 2.14 (Oversize))
- Lincoln, Abraham, 1909, undated; (2 items) (Folder 2.14 (Oversize))
- Lincoln, Abraham, 1913, 1915, 1956, undated; (4 items) (Folder 2.15 (Oversize))
- Lincoln, Abraham, 1909, 1935, undated; (4 items) (Folder 2.16 (Oversize))
- Lincoln, Abraham, undated; (6 items) (Folder M3 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Lincoln, Abraham, 1869; [MISSING as of 11/1/2024] (Folder M8 (Map Case - Drawer ?))
- Lindbergh, Charles A., undated (Folder 2.17 (Oversize))
- Locke, John, 1738 (Folder 2.17 (Oversize))
- Lown, Clarence, undated (Folder 2.17 (Oversize))
- Lowth, Robert, 1809 (Folder 3.01 (Oversize))
- Lydgate, John, undated (Folder 3.01 (Oversize))
- Lynes, George Platt, undated (Folder 3.01 (Oversize))
- MacCracken, Henry Noble, undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.01 (Oversize))
- MacDonald, Rt. Hon. J. Ramsey, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Malebranche, undated (Folder 3.02 (Oversize))
- Manning, undated (Folder 3.02 (Oversize))
- Maria, Countess of Coventry, undated (Folder 3.02 (Oversize))
- Marie, Queen of Romania, 1922 (Folder 3.02 (Oversize))
- Marshall, John, 1877, undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.03 (Oversize))
- Mary, Dutchess of Lancaster, 1758 (Folder 3.03 (Oversize))
- Mary II, Queen, 1744 (Folder 3.03 (Oversize))
- Mary, Queen, The Queen Mother, 1937 (Folder 3.04 (Oversize))
- Masaryk, T. G., undated (Folder M2 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Melchett, Rt. Hon. Lord, of Landford, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Milton, John, 1741 (Folder 3.04 (Oversize))
- Mommsen, Theodor, 1897 (Folder 3.04 (Oversize))
- Montagu, Lady Elizabeth, undated (Folder 3.04 (Oversize))
- Montagu, Mrs., 1809 (Folder 3.05 (Oversize))
- Montgomery, James, 1819 (Folder 3.05 (Oversize))
- Moore, Marianne, undated (Folder 3.05 (Oversize))
- More, Hannah, 1824 (Folder 3.05 (Oversize))
- Morris, William, undated (Folder 3.06 (Oversize))
- Morse, Samuel, undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.06 (Oversize))
- Nelson, Lord Horatio, 1938 (Folder 3.06 (Oversize))
- O'Keefe, Georgia, undated (Folder 3.06 (Oversize))
- O'Neil, Miss, 1816 (Folder 3.07 (Oversize))
- Oastler, Richard, undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.07 (Oversize))
- Pasteur, Louis, undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.07 (Oversize))
- Panizzi, undated (Folder 3.08 (Oversize))
- Peel, Robert, undated (Folder 3.08 (Oversize))
- Pennell, Joseph, undated (Folder 3.08 (Oversize))
- Poe, Edgar Allan, 1930 (Folder 3.09 (Oversize))
- Pomponius Porphyrio, undated (Folder 3.09 (Oversize))
- Prior, Matthew, undated (Folder 3.09 (Oversize))
- Reade, Charles, 1913 (Folder 3.10 (Oversize))
- Rembrandt, undated (Folder 3.10 (Oversize))
- Renan, Ernest, 1823 (Folder 3.10 (Oversize))
- Richardot and Son, 1894 (Folder 3.10 (Oversize))
- Rivera, Prima de, undated (Folder 3.11 (Oversize))
- Rockefeller, John D., undated; (2 items) (Folder 3.11 (Oversize))
- Rogers, Samuel, undated (Folder 3.11 (Oversize))
- Roosevelt, Franklin, 1946, undated; (4 items) (Folder 3.12 (Oversize))
- Roosevelt, Theodore, 1905, 1908; (2 items) (Folder 3.12 (Oversize))
- Rossetti, Christina, 1912 (Folder 4.01 (Oversize))
- Rossetti, D. G., undated (Folder 4.01 (Oversize))
- Rostand, undated (Folder 4.01 (Oversize))
- Rousseau, J. J., undated; (5 items) (Folder 4.02 (Oversize))
- Rousseau, J. J., undated; (2 items) (Folder M6 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Ruskin, John, undated (Folder 4.03 (Oversize))
- Sa Saintete Pie XII, 1939 (Folder 4.03 (Oversize))
- Saltykov, Minhail Eugrafoviah, 1940 (Folder 4.03 (Oversize))
- Sand, George, 1840 (Folder 4.03 (Oversize))
- Savonarola, undated; (2 items) (Folder 4.04 (Oversize))
- Selden, John, undated (Folder 4.04 (Oversize))
- Shakespeare, William, 1719, 1914; (2 items) (Folder 4.04 (Oversize))
- Shaw, George Bernard, undated (Folder 4.05 (Oversize))
- Shelley, Mary Wollstonecraft, undated (Folder 4.05 (Oversize))
- Shelley, Percy Bysshe, undated; (5 items) (Folder 4.05 (Oversize))
- Sherman, William T., undated (Folder 4.06 (Oversize))
- Shuter, Mr., undated (Folder 4.06 (Oversize))
- Simon, Jules, undated (Folder 4.06 (Oversize))
- Simpson, James Alexander, 1936 (Folder 4.06 (Oversize))
- Steer, Philip Wilson, 1929 (Folder 5.08 (Oversize))
- Stokes, Lydia Babbott, undated (Folder 4.07 (Oversize))
- Stuart, Gilbert, 1928 (Folder 4.07 (Oversize))
- Sturge, Joseph, undated (Folder 4.07 (Oversize))
- Swinburne, undated (Folder 4.07 (Oversize))
- Talfourd, Serjieant, undated (Folder 4.08 (Oversize))
- Tennyson, Alfred, undated (Folder 4.08 (Oversize))
- [Tennyson, Alfred ?], undated (Folder 4.08 (Oversize))
- Truman, Harry, 1945 (Folder 4.08 (Oversize))
- Tsar Nicolaievitch, 1905 (Folder 4.09 (Oversize))
- Tsar Nicolaievitch and family, 1905 (Folder 4.09 (Oversize))
- Turgot, undated (Folder 4.09 (Oversize))
- Vassar, John Guy, 1861 (Folder M4 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Venerable, Sally Stokes, VC 1947, 1949 (Folder 4.09 (Oversize))
- Voltaire, undated (Folder 4.09 (Oversize))
- Von Brandenburg, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1875 (Folder 4.10 (Oversize))
- Washington, Mary Ball, and stekches, 1914, 1928; (6 items) (Folder 4.10 (Oversize))
- Washington, George, 1909, 1912, 1957; (3 items) (Folder 5.01 (Oversize))
- Washington, George, 1909, 1926, undated (Folder 5.02 (Oversize))
- Washington, George, 1932, undated; (2 items) (Folder M5 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Wayland, F., undated; (2 items) (Folder 5.03 (Oversize))
- Webster, Daniel, undated (Folder 5.03 (Oversize))
- Whitman, Walt, undated; (3 items) (Folder 5.03 (Oversize))
- William III, King, 1744 (Folder 5.04 (Oversize))
- Wilson, Woodrow, undated (Folder 5.04 (Oversize))
- Wilson, Woodrow, 1918; (2 items) (Folder M5 (Map Case - Drawer 32))
- Wordsworth, William, 1841 (Folder 5.04 (Oversize))
- Wynn, Watkin Williams, 1742 (Folder 5.05 (Oversize))
- Yale, Elihu, 1962 (Folder 5.05 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Man, undated (Folder 5.06 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Woman with Dog, undated (Folder 5.06 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Man, undated (Folder 5.07 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Man, undated (Folder 5.07 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Man, undated (Folder 5.07 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Group, 1911 (Folder 5.07 (Oversize))
- Unidentified Group, undated (Folder 5.07 (Oversize))